## **Mohammad Iqbal Elham**

#### **Full Stack WEB DEVELOPER**

+93765181256 | iqbal.elham7@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio | Wellfound/Angellist

#### **SUMMARY**

Adaptable Full Stack web developer who prizes professional standards, clean code, and cross-cultural skills. Proven readiness for remote work and collaborative pair programming. Swift learner with a growth mindset, equipped to tackle diverse challenges. Proficient in Ruby, Python, React, and JavaScript, technologies honed through my experience at Microverse.

#### **SKILLS**

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Next, Redux, HTML5, CSS3 (Bootstrap, Tailwind)

Back-End: PostgreSQL, SQLite, Python (Django), Ruby on Rails

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Restful, Mobile/Responsive Development, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Pro Futuro Consulting a.s. **Software Developer** 

Remote Dec 2023 – Present

- Engaged in remote collaboration with Zoho, undertaking various projects that involved developing applications within the Zoho ecosystem.
- Specialized in Zoho CRM, Books, People, Inventory, and other apps to provide comprehensive and tailored solutions to clients.
- Leveraged expertise in Deluge Script programming language to develop custom applications as per client specifications.
- Actively participated in the end-to-end development of multiple projects, ensuring timely delivery and high-quality output.

# Netlinks Inc. **Software Development Intern**

On-Site July 2023 – Dec 2023

- Developed and customized Odoo ERP modules using Python, tailoring solutions to meet specific business needs and improve operational efficiency.
- Managed PostgreSQL databases, ensuring optimal performance and data integrity for seamless integration within the Odoo framework.
- Collaborated cross-functionally to analyze, design, and implement solutions, providing technical support and training to end-users while maintaining a focus on data security and system reliability.

- Mentorship of 4 junior web developers, providing hands-on guidance and technical expertise via comprehensive code reviews.
- Spearheaded improvements in code organization and architectural enhancements, resulting in heightened code quality and system performance.
- Instituted motivational strategies and insights to foster long-term program engagement, consistently guiding and inspiring junior developers to navigate challenges and maintain program longevity.

#### **EDUCATION**

MICROVERSE Dec 2022- Oct 2023

#### Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full-Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

#### Kateb University

#### Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science

Aug 2018 - Jul 2022

• A study on the design, development, and analysis of software and hardware used to solve problems in a variety of business, scientific, and social contexts.

### **Extra-Curricular Activities**

## ACM International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC)

Feb 2022

Ranked fourth position out of 47 teams.

## Google Developers Student Club (GDSC) at Kateb University

2020 - 2021

- Core Team member.
- Helping students bridge the gap between theory and practice.
- Provided Seminars, Workshops, and mini-courses related to Google's technologies, such as Android Development.

## ACM International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC)

2019 - 2021

- Co-organizer and IT Technical.
- Building network topologies.
- Configuring the environment and other related works.

## Languages

- Persian native
- English C2, Fluent
- Pashto Fluent